Andrea Giacobino CV

November 11, 2022

General

Solution architect / Software engineer

Personal Info

- Nationality: Italian
- Spoken Languages:
 - Italiano Mother tongue
 - English Professional proficiency
 - Deutsch B-level
 - українська B-level

Contact Information

Location: Berlin/GermanyE-Mail: no.andrea@gmail.com

Links

• Website: adgb.me

• **Github**: github.com/noandrea

• LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/andreagiacobino

• **DevTo**: dev.to/noandrea

Interests

- Decentralized protocols
- Self-sovereign identity (SSI)
- Open source software
- Distributed organizations

Work Projects

Projects in DLT space:

- Cosmos Cash: SSI/SMI and regulatory compliant stablecoin chain; project page (go)
- Coaching/Mentoring: Go mentoring on API development for a Europe based CEX.
- **Provision of private chains**: Go+Docker implementation to simplify the provisioning of private chains (w/Cosmos).
- **DeFi Portal**: Recommendation engine for DeFi protocols on Ethereum for UTU Technologies. Backend and recommendation engine implementation in Go; website
- **Token Crowdsale**: Backend. Implementation in Go on AWS for coordination between KYC/User Interface/Token Contract.
- Go SDK: Aeternity SDK in Go; project page
- Compiler gateway: Smart contract compiler gateway/library for the Aeternity smart contract language: Sophia; project page
- Py SDK: Aeternity SDK in Python; project page

• Faucet: Aeternity testnet faucet; project page

Outside DLT space:

In my career as a software developer, I have worked on several projects of various sizes and complexity. But a recurring pattern has been the focus on data problems, in particular, relative to data manipulation using graph databases or data structures.

Side Projects

Here there are some personal projects for reference.

- **geo2tz**: A service to translate geo coordinates to time zones; project page (go)
- rl2020: Implementation of revocation lists according to the RevocationList2020 w3c proposal; project page (go), project page (rust)
- SafeCMB: A concept around securing a mnemonic phrase backup; project page (rust)
- VALIS: A personal assistant for organizations WIP; website
- CostOf.Life: an exploration of cost management; project page (rust), website
- Distill: URL Shortener; project page (go), website
- The Newsroom: what is the country in the spotlight today (website)

Misc

- Aeternity Forum: forum.aeternity.com/u/noandrea/activity/topics
- Aeternity Talk (2019): youtu.be/F5j8XPK5Gp0?t=18678
- Interview (2019): youtu.be/AgaH-bS1zss

Work experiences (WIP)

I've been working on blockchain projects since the beginning of 2018, starting with PoW chains (Aeternity, Ethereum) and eventually switching to PoS chains; specifically, Tendermint / Cosmos SDK based.

I'm passionate about software development and like to stay close to technology. Still, as a senior staff member, my responsibilities include defining goals and quality criteria as well as planning, prioritization, and active management and moderation to ensure that the project roadmap is implemented correctly and on time.

I focus on engineering and developing blockchain protocols, specifically with Go and Rust.

Tendermint / Ignite

since 2021 (Remote) - tendermint / ignite

Blockchain: Cosmos SDK based
Tools: Git, Docker, CI/CD, K8s

Technologies/Languages: Go, Rust (+WASM), Cosmos-SDK, SSI, Hyperledger Aries

Skills/Roles: Senior Dev, Project Management, Architect

In Tendermint, I've joined a research project about the integration of self-sovereign identity stack and blockchain protocol. The project aims to integrate identity and blockchain solutions with a privacy-respecting approach that is compliant with regulations being drafted in the EU.

As architect, I've designed and implemented several Cosmos-SDK modules for DIDs, verifiable credentials following the W3C standards, as well as implementing different aspects of token economics.

Ape Unit

2018 to 2021 (Berlin, Germany) - website

Blockchain: Ethereum, Cosmos, BSC
Tools: Git, Docker, CI/CD, AWS, K8s

Technologies/Languages: Go, Rust (+WASM), GraphDB

Skills/Roles: Solution Architect, Senior Dev, Project Management

The professional relationship born in the Æternity project has continued within Ape Unit where I followed technical projects focused on DLT technologies.

As a small and dynamic blockchain agency the task at hand are multiple and diverse, I cover different roles from coordination to development and research on technologies and topics in the blockchain sphere. My responsibility is to understand the client domain and then to design technical proposal based on DLT technologies.

Æternity Blockchain

2018 to 2020 (Berlin, Germany) - website. for ApeUnit

Acquired Skills: SDK development, Developer Tools and Technical Documentation, Community Interaction

Tools: GIT, Docker, Kubernetes, CI/CD, AWS, GCP

Technologies/Languages: Python, Go, Rust

Blockchain: Æternity, Ethereum

Skills/Roles: Senior Dev, Project Management

I joined the Æternity project as a maintainer for the python SDK. Over time I got more involved and I started the development of the Go SDK and ended up coordinating the development of the official SDKs, defining development standards, planning releases, engaging with the community and providing support for developers. As the coordinator of the SDKs I worked closely with the core team to provide feedback and ensuring smooth transitions across protocol upgrades and node releases

In the project I was also involved in moderating sessions for discussing off-protocol standards (AEXs) and providing support to some of the exchanges (Binance, Huobi, OKEx)

Welance Ventures UG

2017 to 2019 (Berlin, Germany) - website

Tools: GIT, Docker, AWS

Technologies/Languages: MySQL, Python, PHP, Apache, Nginx

data migration, development experience, training

Titel Media GmbH / Highsnobiety

2017 to 2019 (Berlin, Germany) - website

Tools: GIT, Docker, AWS, GCP, K8s

Technologies/Languages: Go, SQL

I've met Highsnobiety's CTO for the first time in the summer of 2017 where they had a "simple" goal, keeping the page load time for Highsnobiety under the google recommendation at all time, both for cached and non-cached

content. I have worked with them to identify the bottlenecks of their stack and we managed to achieve substantial improvement in the non-cached area. After that I kept consulting with them for various infrastructure related decision and to develop ad hoc solution for data management. The most exciting moment has been the migration from one cloud provider to another while simultaneously switching from puppet to k8s with 0 downtime.

Tykli Srl (co-founder)

2012 to 2017 (L'viv, Ukraine/Berlin, Germany)

Acquired Skills: Project management, budgeting, distributed systems, infrastruc-

ture scaling

Tools: GIT, AWS, Maven, SonarQube

Technologies/Languages: Java, Spark, Scala, Python, Postgres

With a colleague of mine we founded a startup whose goal was to provide a data analysis platform able to provide semantic insight into large and unstructured datasets. The underling core technology was built using graphs and graph theory as the base to infer meaning from unknown data. My responsibility was to design and develop the platform and the infrastructure and to write the algorithms in a way that the computation could be easily distributed.

The technology won a contest for innovation and was later acquired by Ennova Group.

Emerasoft Srl

2008 to 2012 (Torino, Italy) - website

Tools: Subversion, Polarion ALM, Jenkins, SonarQube

Technologies/Languages: Java

I've joined Emerasoft as a junior php/java developer to work on custom editorial solutions based on php, java and InDesign server. The focus was to create custom workflow for validation of graphic contents for printing.

Since 2010 my responsibilities shifted to research and evaluate new trends in the devops field and to promote best practices in the organization and to the customers. Meanwhile I was managing an outsourcing team focused on developing an editorial solution for a big manufacturing company.

Over time I graduated from R&D to professional services where I was responsible to design and implement ALM workflows, using Polarion/Subversion as the platform and to coordinate the deployment in medium/large organizations. The main focus was to create organization-wide policy for development and management of software projects. In this role I had the opportunity to work with different realities such as banks, insurance companies, manufacturing companies, public administration.

Education

I do routinely attend to online courses as well as using other sources to keep up with the evolution of the technology.

The following is a summary of the formal education.

University

Informatica (Torino, Italy) - website

Course: information technology

I have studied in the faculty of information technology. I haven't got a bacelor degree but I have completed 90% of the course.

High school

Liceo Classico (Torino, Italy) - website

Focus: literature, history and philosophy

I have graduated from the liceo classico in Torino.